We have an app called Casper Pro Webcam,
which was our COVID panic pivot that
actually saved the company.
>> Whoa. Well, we have to dive into that.
>> Thankfully, an accidental excellent
business decision many years ago, I
pulled out the camera connection logic
and stuff into its own framework. That
is another revenue stream for the
company like we license that out. We
went, "Oh, oh, we could use the SDK to
make a webcam, a virtual webcam on the
Mac." So, you can connect your camera
and then it's a webcam. So from like
idea to money was 3 weeks and I'm very
proud of that. That filled in the
revenue.
>> Welcome to Launched. I'm Charlie Chapman
and today I'm excited to bring you the
developer behind the excellent
photography app Cascal, Daniel Kennet.
>> Daniel, welcome to the show.
>> Thank you. Nice to be here.
>> We got to hang out a little bit uh a
couple weeks ago in Chicago, right, for
Deep Dish Swift. And you were a speaker
there. And for a while there, you were
top tier, the funniest by a significant
margin, uh talk, also guest of the show
a long time ago, Chad Zel. He came in
towards the last minute and he's
competing with you. Those were both like
some of the funniest talks I think I've
ever seen.
>> That was my favorite talk at that
conference. It was so good.
>> Highly recommend people people watch
that. Uh so yeah, I'm super excited to
to have you on. Uh as soon as I saw that
and honestly as soon as I saw or
listened to the podcast that you did
leading up to uh that conference that
they do, I was like, "All right, it's
time." Uh you've been on my list for a
very long time and we need to make this
happen. And so uh I'm glad I'm glad
you're finally here.
>> Thank you. It's nice to be here. Yeah.
>> So before we get into, you know, your
backstory uh and how you ended up making
Cascal, uh I want you to explain what
Cascal is. give the quick elevator pitch
so that we know kind of what we're
leading up to here.
>> We have a few apps, but the main app,
Cascable Studio, is for photographers
with cameras that aren't iPhones. So,
like we support Canon, Nikon, Sony,
Fujifilm, like a few others.
And it they it connects to your camera
and you can remote control it, transfer
files across. But we also have more
advanced features like automation and
like all the way up to like a shortcuts
like visual scripting language for
photographers to like automate doing
this and that. So it's like a more
professional
um you know like advanced uh like
amateur photographers use it as well
especially for like astrophotography and
stuff like that. It's it's a tool in
that realm for like advanced amateurs
and professional photographers to do
more with their camera uh than they can
with what it comes with.
>> Perfect. And uh all right, let's get
into you know how you ended up uh
building these apps. And so the
questions I always ask to kind of uh
kick off this conversation is where are
you from? Uh do you have a formal
education related to what you do? And
then yeah, what was your career like
that kind of led you into the sort of
indie app world?
>> I grew up in England. I live in Sweden.
So now I'm from Sweden, but I'm from
from England. I guess I have had formal
computing education in the form of a
computer science degree. I shipped my
first India app and started earning
money from it before that degree
started. Man, you really pitched this as
a really complicated story and then you
just bing bang bong answered them uh
very cleanly.
>> Well, yeah. Yeah, that's true. Yeah, but
like everything's kind of all over the
place and and stuff.
>> So, you have a computer science degree,
but you started doing the indie thing
before that. So, yeah. What's the story
there? Why did you start doing that?
>> All right. All right, the whole thing
started. Do do you as an American know
what a car boot sale is?
>> I know what a car boot is. Uh cuz I've
seen Harry Potter.
>> Um so uh I know that that is that is
what we call a trunk of the car, right?
The part that you can open in the back.
>> Maybe a flea market is closed. Like a
bunch of people put all of their sec
crap they want to get rid of and
everybody drives to a field somewhere
and it's all in the boots of their cars.
They open the car boot. People come,
they wander around and they buy
secondhand stuff.
>> Oh wow. Okay. So, we have garage sales.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like a garage sale that everybody
comes together into one place.
>> This feels like something that should be
an American thing given our, you know,
obsession with cars and big old
>> You do like your cars.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Anyway, so um when I was a kid, we
bought a uh a ZedX Spectrum computer
from there. It was like the era where it
had a tape drive, like Atari kind of
Commodore kind of thing. It was way
obsolete by the time we got it, but you
could still buy games on tape from like
secondhand stores at at that time. And
you could buy magazines and it was the
kind of era where there'd be a program
in the magazine and you type, it was
basic. And that kind of got me into oo
programming cool. And then, you know, my
family, my dad was a journalist and that
industry was Mac back then. So like they
had a a Mac in the office. When that Mac
became obsolute, it came to my bedroom.
So that was a Mac LC2, so like system 7
era kind of 90s.
Um, and I really wanted to learn how to
program it. And I did several failed
attempts to do that. Like I tried Java.
I like from a local bookstore bought a
Java book. The first sweet solution,
right?
>> Yeah. Didn't really get on with it. I
tried cuz back then it was all C and
C++, right? So I tried that. Didn't
really get on with it. Um after a few
years few failed attempts I found a
thing called real basic which is like a
crossplatform visual basic kind of
language. So it's quite simple and I did
and I did manage to like get on with
that and actually learn programming with
it and I started sort of making apps and
shipping them.
>> Yeah. What is shipping apps mean in this
era?
>> Yeah. So that would be uploading it to a
website in a sit file stuff expander and
it' list it on version tracker.com which
is just a list of things that were
released basically.
>> Okay. Interesting. So it's like sort of
shareware minus the
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. And
back then like people would pay the
payment provider called Kaji K AJI not
the search engine. And then I remember
my first check from them in dollars came
when I was 15. So that it's kind of that
era
>> in dollars. So people are people were
able to pay you cross country even then.
Was that complicated?
>> Well, it probably should have been. Um
they paid the payment provider and then
they would just send me a check for
everything. But it was an American
company, so literally I just get in the
mail like, you know, a month after they
sent it a check dollars.
>> That's pretty cool.
>> Um Yeah. Yeah. It was cool. Uh, and I
remember 15 cuz we went to the bank and
the bank would not let me open a
business account cuz I wasn't 16 yet.
And I kind of did this mostly on my own
like um
valition cuz where it might have been
the time, it might have been the
location, it might have been both, but
schools where I grew up and when I grew
up didn't really have computing courses.
Like there was a computer on a cart that
would get wheeled in once a week and
we'd go on the computer, you know, and
even when I got to secondary school,
which is ages 11 to 16. Then even there,
it was a huge school and there was a
computer room and like once a week we'd
all file into the computer room and
learn how to use word and mail merging
and all that kind of stuff. So like that
degree was the first actual programming
education I got.
>> And what kind of app what kind of app
were you making?
>> It was a word processor. It was a very
simp like kind of like text edit but a
bit more fancy. Like if I'm honest, it
was just like dragging controls onto a
screen and like you know, oh, you type
text here and you can change the font
and stuff. You know, that kind of earned
pocket money. I saved up and bought my
iPod with that. Biked over to the local
Apple reseller. That was before Apple
stores, I think, especially in the UK.
Uh, bought my iPod with my with my app
money. Um, yeah. And then the iPod
actually unlocked my first indie
business. Oh, really? Okay. At the kind
of tail end of my preun university
education, um I had an iBook and I want
I had music on my iPod and I wanted to
share it with my friends, but iTunes
wouldn't let you copy music from the
iPod back to a computer. Um I guess it
was a copyright thing. So wait, you buy
cuz you had to buy the music on your
computer and share it to your iPad.
What's the story for why you're then
sharing from the iPad to a computer?
It's because it's your friend's
computer. you know, this is the height
of the Napster era, you know, all that
kind of stuff. So, it's like, "Oh, I got
this cool new album. You should listen
to it. I've got it on my iPod. I'll give
you a copy."
>> And they have their computer with them.
>> Yeah. If I go around to their house, you
know, they've got a computer there or
whatever.
>> So, I started figuring out um
how the iPod worked and reverse
engineering it a bit and figuring out
how to get the music back off it.
>> This is feeling like origin stories
already for Gasco, but
>> Oh, 100%. Yeah. So, I did that in the
back of physics. So my physics grades
just went
in the last
>> when you said on the back of physics I
thought you meant you were using
physics. I'm like what?
>> Literally sitting in the back of the
classroom tapping away on my computer
rather than paying attention to my
physics lesson and physics was the
science I was good at as well. It was
really stupid. I ended up like shipping
it again similar thing uploaded to a
website very very basic license key
system. Thankfully, thankfully, even
though my grades at school tanked, I
think because I did computer sciency
stuff and I put the fact I was making
apps and shipping them like on my
application to uni, they still let me in
for my computer science degree. Even
though I um missed the like grades
required by quite quite a margin.
>> And you said real business. So, was this
one like making like actual, you know,
not just pocket money, but like a real
amount of money?
>> Not then, but it did. I was doing uni,
learning how to program properly, you
know, with proper like programming and
then I was still doing this app, this
this iPod app in the sort of in the
background, you know, while doing that
and it was just very slowly like, you
know, ticking upwards. Uh, and that
course was supposed to have a work
placement in the third year. I was like,
I should do my app in that instead. And
the university wouldn't let me work for
myself for my workplacement
>> because they want they want what they're
really wanting is like learn how to work
with people, learn how to write a BRD or
agile or whatever was popular at the
time.
>> Exactly. And the rule that they dinged
me on was that um you can't have the
report given back to the university on
your progress be written by a member of
your family.
>> Oh yeah. Which
>> and I am a member of my own family.
Yeah. It's hard to argue my way out of
that one. But what they did instead let
me do is change my degree to a computer
science degree without a work placement
and then just take a gap year. So I did
that and in that year I worked on it
full-time, you know, cuz I still in the
umbrella of education and living in my
parents house, you know, all that kind
of stuff. And by the end of that year,
it was like properly, you know, a
business. So I'm curious, you said it
was ticking up and up and then by giving
it full time, it it grew more. Why do
you think it was starting to, you know,
it's not just features, like were you
marketing it or was it being shared
around?
>> What happened was I was kind of
following the the the the rise of the
iPod, if you like.
>> Oh, that's you're sort of doing the same
thing that a lot of people did with the
iPhone, right?
>> Yeah. Exactly. And I think I never
really did any proper marketing for it,
but you know, by that time there were a
ton of competitors. A lot of them were
free. Mine wasn't, but I I tried to do a
really good job of making it a very
friendly app.
So like it would auto detect the color
of your iPod and the icon in the app was
the same color as your iPod, you know,
little details like that
>> which the Mac community especially in
that time.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Highly appreciated. Yeah.
>> And it was also crossplatform. It was
real basic and that would compile from
Windows for me. So I shipped it on Mac
and Windows. And uh what really really
gave it its break I think was there was
a popular website at the time called
iPod Lounge that became iLounge when the
phone came out. and that did a tutorial
on how to copy music from your iPod to
your Mac. The business kind of sales
pitch was that it's for backup. So if
your Mac fails, you know, your hard
drive fails, you have a backup of all of
your music and the playlists and the
smart plays, everything. Your iPod is
basically a mirror of it. So the app
would recover all that. The playlist,
the smart playlist, a lot. So it just
mirror it back basically.
>> Was that how you marketed it as well?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. It was like and it was
genuinely used for that. Like by by the
end like we were getting people referred
to us by Apple support like saying,
"Hey, Apple said like I I need you to
get my stuff back." I Yeah, sure. But
this iPod lounge website did a tutorial
on how to do that. And they used my app,
Music Rescue, it was called to do that.
And that was just so if somebody they
had really high SEO, they were like a
proper SEO, you know, place. if you also
visted um how to you know recover music
from my iPod they would get that article
which would get my app
>> and that is an argument for why spending
a bunch of time on features and polish
and everything matters because like the
reason they chose that I'm imagining is
because it was the easiest one to do an
article on because it's like it's more
straightforward they're going to get way
less people asking them questions than
if they had picked some free like really
janky thing. Um so yeah that's that's a
case where like doing the the feature
work even if it doesn't immediately lead
to marketing uh actually can have that
impact you know down the road.
>> Exactly. Yeah. I always find it funny
when people these days are like well you
know you have to use X programming
language or X framework to build an app.
So, come on. I I bought a house with
real basic like you know is a users
don't care if it's a good app and it's
it fits well in the platform you know
it's polished then you know the
underlying technology isn't really super
important you know obviously the
technology helps you do that
>> and depending on the specific audience
you know maybe they care but very likely
that's not the case
>> your average end user doesn't care
between UI kit and swift UI or whatever
you know so yeah that that breeze past
the next few years finished uni was
earning enough money to like you know
pay a mortgage all that stuff the lot.
Um next 2 three years completely screwed
it up like completely screwed it up.
Ended up with like I avoided bankruptcy
like like this like by the skin of my
teeth like the skin of my teeth. How did
I screw it up or how did I avoid
bankruptcy?
>> How did you screw it up? What happened
was is
two two real things is a a a kid
basically with no financial education in
like maybe two years went from working
in a hardware store part-time to pay for
food at uni to earning like a senior
developer salary. This is like the
football player
>> story, right? Like saving. Nah, I just
like, you know, buy stuff. Credit card,
credit card. Oh, credit cards maxed out.
Pay it all off. Whole thing, right? And
and do that. So then separately, we also
like, you know, I hired a friend. We had
an idea for a new thing like another app
which we were both excited about and we
started building that and like we kind
of spread everything too thin. The
revenue from music rescue just started
to drop a bit. Not a lot like it just it
just you know the iPod you know the
phone was out by this time the industry
had changed how music was consumed was
changing like Spotify is coming out a
lot you know so our revenue started to
kind of do that a bit but because I was
basically just spending without thought
on kind of a delay as well because of
credit cards and stuff you know by the
time I realized it was kind of too late.
Um, so between this just just being crap
with money basically and and not saving
and not doing sensible smart things,
>> not really anticipating the fact that
this wasn't just the way it was going to
be forever.
>> Exactly. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, cuz I had
no idea. Yeah. And then everything just
kind of came crashing down basically.
>> Did that just like upend your sort of
mental model for your self-worth? Like
were you very tied up in this as that
was your thing or was it like you know
you did this other stuff and you had
this cool little side hobby that
happened to be making money?
>> No, no, that was my thing. That was like
it was the worst time of my life. Like
it really was like
>> I imagine not just the money but also
that like identity.
>> Exactly. The whole thing. I struggled
with this since then but I my identity
was always developer programmer rather
than business person. So like you know
you know failing that way didn't really
shake my confidence as a developer.
>> Oh okay that makes sense.
>> It just really sucked. So we you know
lost a car just you know suddenly came
and took the car one day. Uh fighting to
keep the house. Uh I eventually sold it
to avoid it being taken basically. Um
you know lost lost friends everything
like my my entire life was like kind of
destroyed. Um, so what we did in a in a
very sensible move was to I know we
should move to Sweden.
>> That's the go-to uh go-to move, right?
>> Famously
cheap place to live,
>> right?
>> Cuz the thing is the company was the app
was still selling like it was earning
some money. So in theory there was a
universe where I could have like kind of
sorted it all out and carried on. Uh,
and the way I work is it's very hard for
me to
I I I deal better with troubleshooting
like looking in from the outside. So if
I'm inside the problem, especially
literally my house is, you know, I'm in
the house and they're threatening to
take it away.
>> Was there was this a little bit of like
sort of running away from your problems
>> but at the time I was like, "No, no, no.
We planned this for quite a while." If
you had like, you know, it's all
sensible, blah, blah, I was basically
fleeing the country.
It was within the EU at the time, so
obviously I wasn't fleeing crap really
cuz you know
>> more like mentally, right? You needed a
>> reset. Yeah, exactly. Just just outside
of the physical space I was in. Yeah. Um
and I tried and like I eventually I just
ended up folding the company. Like I
just went, you know, this isn't this
isn't going to come back. I don't think
so. Folded it. Still had a ton of
personal debt. Um ended up working at
Spotify.
>> That's what I was going to ask. Why why
Sweden? Uh, and Spotify feels like Was
it because of Spotify or was it like you
just liked Sweden?
>> The actual story is Obama got elected.
>> Oh, okay. You don't need to explain
anymore. That's why you end up in
Sweden. Yeah.
>> Yeah, obviously. Um, yeah. There's this
whole thing in the media, I think, in
American media how Obama was going to
turn America into like a socialist hell
hole. Uh, and the Daily Show did a a bit
on like, oh, it's America's going to
turn like turn out like horrible crappy
Sweden. Um, and they did like a
documentary on how terrible Sweden won.
And the bit was it's actually a really
nice place.
>> So they like accidentally did an ad
campaign for like move
>> pretty much. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And I was
like, "Oh, we should move to Sweden."
Yeah. And it was a joke and then just
like over a year it just kind of like
snowballed into like, you know, like cuz
my wife and I were fairly young
at the time. Um, and uh, we were like,
"Okay, well, if we're going to
experience living in a foreign country,
it's either now or when we're retired."
So I was like, we'll move to Sweden for
a year. We can rent, you know, figure
out this whole cash flow situation with
my previous company, you know. Um, so we
moved, yeah, with with without Spotify
at all. And I've been there for six,
we've been there six
months or so, maybe a bit less. It's not
important. Uh, and
when we made the decision to fold the
company, it's like, okay, well, I do did
still have all this debt that I needed
to deal with. So I was, okay, well, we
needed I need to get a job then. Uh, and
a friend of mine on Twitter, um, when it
was good, um, worked at Spotify, um, and
we were we were Twitter friends and he
was like, "You should, uh, you should
come work for Spotify." And then I I
went for a chat one day, uh, and it was
an interview. I didn't realize it was an
interview. I
>> That's the best way to go into an
interview.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I think so. And then I ended
up getting the job at Spotify, so
>> Oh, that's cool. That's a fun time to be
at Spotify, too, right?
>> It was. Yeah. Yeah. I So, I joined
before they were launched in the US.
>> Wow. very small. We went to WWDC and
nobody had any clue who we were. Like
never heard of it.
>> I was, you know, a Groove Shark user who
was just like constantly pouring over
screenshots of Spotify waiting for it to
come to the US. Maybe I even got the Mac
app before cuz I think you could
download the app. You just couldn't
create
>> You could download the app.
>> Maybe I created an account with a VPN.
I'm trying to remember. I remember being
very excited about Spotify specifically.
>> It was really cool and it was really
early. The company was really
>> Oh, that's pretty cool. And yeah, the
time I was there was like a really huge
growth period. Like I was employee
number 10 and something and it was many
thousand many thousand by the time I
left four years later. So that was a
bonkers time. It was fun. I learned a
bunch of stuff that you don't learn
being an indie developer like how to
work with people.
>> And were you doing indie stuff at all
during this time or were you like I'm a
company man?
>> I was just like right no that's done.
Just need to concentrate on like sorting
out all the debt paying that off like
getting that all sorted out. And it was
a really fun job. So, I didn't really
want to like the the itch wasn't there
as it were. Like I was having a great
time doing what I was doing at Spotify.
Like I was, you know, sorting everything
out. It was good. And then once
everything was sorted out, you know, all
the previous bad stuff was done,
everything, you know, settled. I bought
a camera and it was the first Canon
camera that had Wi-Fi. And I was like,
"Oo, Wi-Fi." Um, and the app was
terrible. Like really terrible. And I
was like, I could make a better app than
this. I should reverse engineer this
camera. And then 12 years later, here I
am talking to you. Bang. Boom. All
right. Roll the credits.
>> Pretty much. Yeah.
>> So, when when you say app, you mean the
desktop app for letting you Or is this a
phone app?
>> No, it was a phone app.
>> This is a phone app, right? Right.
That's the point of the Wi-Fi.
>> The Wi-Fi was slow.
It wasn't terrible because all it did
was take the USB kind of interface and
just pipe it over TCIP basically. So you
had access to everything even though
Candace app didn't give you everything.
Oh, so you weren't using any like APIs,
fancy APIs or anything. You could just
connect to it because it was just the I
guess USB protocol over Wi-Fi. Is that a
thing? I don't I don't know much about
that. Yeah, there's like a standard um
protocol for cameras called PTP which is
picture transfer protocol and then there
is a standard for funneling that over IP
which is IP experience with this kind of
thing because of all this time you
spent.
>> Well, but you were
>> reverse engineering. Yes. So I
>> just reverse engineering but like piping
files over USB protocols.
>> Yeah, exactly. Like I the the iPod was
mostly disc based so that was okay. Um,
but there there was some funny stuff
that like to figure out the color you
there was the iPod had a P list embedded
like you heard of scuzzy?
>> Yes, I know that I know the word scuzzi.
It's a cable, right? Or like a protocol.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Like a like a protocol. So
it turns out a lot a USB is kind of sort
of scuzzy over a different cable. So you
could issue some scuzzy commands to the
iPod to get a P list out of it. And
>> that's the most like Apple,
>> right? I imagine none of this existed uh
with Canon.
>> No, no, no, no, no. Um, yeah. So, like I
did it, you know, kind of learned
reverse engineering kind of through that
really.
>> And so, you built this, you built this
for yourself then or was it initially,
was it immediately like, oh, I'm going
to make an app and kind of sell it
somewhere?
>> No, we were still kind of reeling from
what had happened.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, this is just a side
project. Like, it it scratched the itch
of doing like a reverse engineering
stupid. I love doing stupid stuff with
computers. It's the best. It was just
kind of like a fun side project to to
learn how this works and stuff. Um, and
then just over time, like as Spotify
grew, you know, it became a massive
corporation like any massive
corporation. Uh, I was never that good
at the corporate like career game. You
know, I filling out the boxes to check
to do this thing. I don't know. So like
promotion projects and
>> yeah the company kind of grew around me
um if you like. So like I was just kind
of in the middle with way more people
above and way more people below just
picking out Jira tickets and fixing the
jury ticket you know it got like I I did
some amazing amazing things at Spotify
but like by the end I was just kind of
like bored of it. uh not not bored of
the work I was doing but just you know
being in a big corporation and not kind
of sucking at at the promotion game and
just watching people join you know way
after me and get promoted ahead of me
you know that kind of thing
>> and so the side project is during this
period of like you're starting to get
bored you're just kind of it's a fun
tinker thing
>> yeah exactly yeah and it got to a point
it's like ah this could be enough I
could sell this we could do it my wife
and I talked when all this was happening
with my previous company she was my
girlfriend like we we were we weren't
even engaged at the time and she saw
She saw him.
>> Oh, she lived it. Yeah. Like we hadn't
been together that long like um as well,
but she stayed
>> um which is kind of crazy, but but she
saw it. So she she had also kind of
lived it and she'd seen the worst of it
and she
very understandably was also not super
enthusiastic about like let's do it
again. Perfect. So, but she she
supported me and we we set some like
sensible goals like um so I had some
savings by then and in Sweden the law is
once a company is a big enough size
they're obliged to give an employee 6
months off unpaid and guarantee their
job is still there at the end. Um you
know just for for any kind of sbatical.
So I took that and the idea was okay at
the 6 months if the app isn't selling
you
cut and go back
>> and you hadn't released it already by
this point.
>> No, no, it it was getting there. So I
spent a month or so after I, you know,
started my sobatical from Spotify
working on it full-time, finishing it
up, polishing it, making it an act
rather than just a side project. So then
it shipped a month or so into into that
spectacle and then the most annoying
thing happened was it didn't make the it
was nowhere near you know replacing my
salary but like the the line it was very
consistently sort of growing.
>> You released it just for context it was
on the Mac App Store or was this through
your website?
>> Oh right iOS app store. Yeah. Yeah.
>> So it was on the iOS app store. Okay.
And it was a paid upfront or
subscription like what was the business
model?
>> It was going to be a paid upfront iPad
only app which is stupid like nobody
would have bought it.
>> I mean you say that but there's some
major successes that are paid.
>> There are Yeah. But
>> those are more broad appeal than
>> Yeah. Just some random guy making an app
that worked with like three cameras like
>> a friend of mine did convince me to make
it work on the iPhone as well. So thank
you to him. Um but it was still paid up
front with 1.0 which was stupid. like
nobody bought it cuz you wouldn't,
right? So that was part of it and quite
quickly it went like, you know, free
within app purchase to unlock anything
interesting and
>> but like a one-time purchase kind of
thing.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Yeah. So then
I my wife and I sat down and we had
discussions and then we kind of set
rolling goals to make sure it was still
going the right way and to and basically
avoid what happened last time which was
being caught by surprise by anything. So
we we were paying close attention to how
it was doing, making sure that you know
everything was was you know going in the
right direction. Picked up contracting
part time to fill in the gap. Yeah.
>> This is relevant I think for the future
part of the story. But like your wife is
a product manager or
>> Yeah. So um at that time my wife also
worked at Spotify and she was in the
business development team for Spotify
>> which part of these conversations you
can already feel even though she's not
you know an employee of the company. Uh
>> yeah yeah yeah
>> she's bringing a little bit of business
rigor uh that maybe we didn't have the
first time.
>> Yes. Yep. Yep. Yep. So yeah so we we you
know did that and then slowly the app
developed over a number of years and did
part-time contracting to to fill in the
gap of salary.
>> Did it continue that same kind of steady
growth the whole time?
>> Mostly yes. um it gets frustratingly
flat at times
like we've never had a serious like
backslide in income but we have had
periods where it's just like no matter
what we do it's just like a flat line
which is great in it's you know you can
rely on it. Um but if you need it to be
more to hit a goal of quitting
contracting or whatever it's very
frustrating because you like you're
doing new features marketing all this
stuff it's just like flatline like
>> through all of this time it was like a
one time inapp purchase.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. We we experiment with
a few things cuz I I I always and it's
kind of gone away now I feel. But
there's this race to the bottom for a
while where apps are expected to be
cheap, like super cheap. And I was like,
"Nah, no, no, no, no." Um, if you can
afford $4,000 for a camera, you can pay
more than $2 for my app, right? Um, it
was always not super cheap, but like for
a while we did feature packs where like
if you only wanted the remote control
automation stuff, you could just buy
that part of the app for $10 or whatever
and or this and that and then you could
buy the whole lot for 30 I think at the
time. Eventually I got rid of that cuz
just it doesn't scale.
>> And kind of the point of the app is that
it's a lot simpler to use than these
other tools. Right.
>> Exactly. So we got we didn't really get
any backlash at all for that. Nobody
cared um because most people bought the
full feature pack anyway.
What do you think the the main driver
for that continued growth was then? Cuz
like you were late enough that it wasn't
like you were just riding the iOS or the
the iPhone growth, right? Cuz for a long
time that was apps were growing just
because of that. Kind of like you were
with the iPad initially and then you're
you're paid upfront. So it's only new
users who are coming in. And it doesn't
from what we've talked about in the past
and what you're saying here, it doesn't
sound like you were doing these big
marketing campaigns or paid acquisition
or whatever. So, what do you think was
causing it to go up? Cuz I would expect
it to be relatively flat. Here's a fact
for you that I learned recently. B&H,
which is a photo store in New York, I
believe they only have the one store.
The photography market is huge. It's
absolutely ginormous. So, I think we're
just reaching more people. Um, I think a
lot of it, especially with how it went,
was word of mouth. We'd always like, you
know, we post on social media and we'd
try and, you know, post on social media
like Reddit, things like that. We'd try,
every time we do a big update, we try
and get in photography publications,
websites, and stuff. We'd get covered
sometimes. So, I think just very slowly
we just got to more people.
>> That's pretty cool.
>> Okay. It's very interesting to me
because we like a highlight of my career
is like as there's a smaller camera
manufacturer here in Scandinavia that
makes very very large cameras like big
huge chunky things and they didn't have
a mobile app.
>> These are like large frame large format
kind of cameras.
>> Medium for it's called medium format
even though it's like absolutely
enormous
>> and they came to us and said hey can can
your app be our app?
>> We're like yeah cool. So we like worked
out like a you know an agreement and
they sent us hardware and they paid for
the development cost. Was this like a
white label thing or is it literally
they're going to
>> No. So we No. So basically if you
download our app from the app store,
connect one of their cameras, you get
the app just like tada, it's free now.
>> Oh, that's pretty cool.
>> Yeah. That we talked about white
labeling, but I was like I I mean we
could we can
um it would be simpler and cheaper if we
just did it this way instead. And they
they kind of like that as well.
>> Well, and it helps with probably ASO or
whatever. you know, there's more users
using the app regularly and probably
giving better reviews cuz it's free.
Yeah, that makes sense.
>> And then so we announced we launched an
update with that in and like some other
features for everyone else. And we got
like like a drink. So um it just
everything lifted with that even though
for those folks it was free. So the the
income wasn't coming from this new
camera manufacturer. So
>> So it's not just users, your income did
go up.
>> Yeah. Yeah. our income went up and I
think people good at marketing probably
know this there's an actual word for it
but I think it um added like legitimacy
to our name almost cuz you know if you
search for our app and there's like oh
this camera manufacturer has announced
using you know cascal studio as their
app as their like you know first party
kind of app it kind of adds legitimacy
to the name and I think I think that
helped
>> I imagine also just he like ASO like you
know if there's suddenly way more people
using it and it's ranking higher uh and
the app store is seeing those usage
analytics going up I think all that
stuff goes into how highly you are
ranked you know for certain words
>> I think I I think so
>> and that probably benefits everything
else you know in terms of uh in terms of
like acquisition through the store.
Yeah, I think so. And then from that
bump, we were able like I haven't done
like the company or I have not had to do
any kind of consulting for other people
since then. So since then the app and
its products like support, you know, the
salary and things like that and that was
2020. So that would have been like five
or six years after the app launched, it
actually earned me a salary on its own.
So it took you know a long long long
time.
>> Now we haven't really talked a lot about
the app itself. So, you know, initially
you built it as a way to do Wi-Fi uh
pulling pictures off of your Canon
camera, but obviously it's a lot more
than that. So, like what what did it
kind of grow up to be um when you were
in that period of like let's make this
for everybody?
>> So, there are two avenues for growth and
of of this is adding more cameras and
then adding more features. And for a
while, we just kind of threw features at
the wall. That's not
like I can't attribute any
single feature to it, you know, growing
up. Like I I joke that the app has been
done for about 4 years now. Um cuz it
does, you know, it's it's a fully
featured solid app. Like and what what
are the features? Cuz like it's not
just, you know, pulling pictures off of
your camera now, right?
>> The app is split into kind of almost
modules. So there's there's a remote
control module. So you can connect to
the camera, see what it sees, change the
camera settings, take pictures, record
video, and automate taking pictures and
recording video basically. Um, uh, you
know, and the automations are fairly
advanced in that they, you know, take a
picture, record a video, whatever.
Change settings do the same. And, um,
you know, we've, we've seen people, it's
a really nice spike in the analytics
every time something happens in space.
So like you know if there's an eclipse
or a meteor shower or something like
that we just seeing like all all our
automations just go through the roof on
the analytics. Oh that's kind of funny
because yeah I imagine that is you know
not only is it a big spike in people
taking more advanced kind of photos but
it's also like specifically the group of
people that don't have custom hardware
for it who just want to do it for this
one event or whatever. They're going to
be like ah how what's the best way to do
a time lapse? I have a tripod but like
I'm not going to or a focus puller or I
don't know whatever random thing you
need for different types of events. Do
you like think about those at this point
as oh this event's coming up let's do a
push leading up to it?
>> We are um all right a year ago my wife
joined the company and that's one of the
things she's working on. Yeah is do
we've been talking about it for years
cuz it makes total sense but um I just
never did it.
>> I mean it is a job. It's almost like you
have to build out a calendar of like
here's all the events we think could
happen and then work backwards in terms
of how do you promote leading up to it.
Um oh that's that's really it'll be
interesting to to see how that plays out
cuz it does feel like what we you know
in marketing world uh we always call
compelling events. It's like this is an
event that other people are seeking out
a solution suddenly and so you should be
there ready. So yeah, our marketing
things we're going to try and work on is
that and actually making video content
and not not not just instructional
videos, but like just making a
compelling set of content for people
just to discover us through. Um, again,
you'd think photography video company
would do that, but I'm I'm I don't know.
So you said uh you you you know, you'd
make lots of features and you felt like
you were kind of throwing those on the
wall, but the other side of the coin was
adding new cameras. And my guess, uh,
you can tell me if I'm wrong, but I
would imagine that each camera and
especially each manufacturer that you
added was a sudden like you could
probably see that change the metrics
because that opens up the sort of the
TAM for your business.
>> Yeah, manufacturers in particular. Yeah,
cuz we tend to release
um like our big releases are a new
manufacturer cuz they they tend to but
not always have like a common stack for
their for their all their cameras. So,
you know, Canon was first and we added
Nikon and that was just like we now
support every Nikon camera in the past
10 years or something. Off you go. Um
and that that brings in a swath of new
users. Um we haven't done that in a
while and all the camera manufacturers
that are left are small manufacturers.
So, I don't know
if uh our next one to do is Leica, for
instance.
>> That was the one I actually my brain
went to. I didn't know if she supported
them or not, but they feel like uh while
they're small, it's also an audience
that is well, one willing to spend
money. And two, it does feel like
weirdly Leica is a little bit more
proumer.
Yes. So, people buy Leas are people who
really care about photography. So, I
think that would be a good one to add,
but I'm not sure.
>> But it also feels like a tinkery crowd,
right?
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Like there's probably lots of, you know,
professional photographers obviously
that shoot with Leica, obviously, but
like
>> it almost feels like there is this
subgenre of just if you have a Leica
camera, you're the type of person who
has lots of gear and plays with lots of
things and tries lots of things, but it
is obviously smaller than, you know,
Nikon or or Canon or something.
>> Exactly. Yeah. and they're very
expensive and we we have to buy the
cameras to to do it.
>> Yeah. I I want to touch on that because
it was funny whenever I was talking to
you uh in Chicago a couple weeks ago. I
I think I made some joke about like,
man, it must be nice to to have to use
your business expense for buying all
these cameras. And you sort of lamented
it because yes, you have to buy lots of
camera bodies,
>> but that also means you don't have a lot
of cameras you can actually really
functionally use for the business.
>> Yes. Yeah. There's two reasons why it's
kind of sad. So the first one is like if
you want to start an indie app business,
choosing a thing where you need to buy
lots of very expensive hardware to get
going is a really bad idea just
objectively like cuz you know and
secondly yeah like if you care about
photography we have cameras that people
would like I know people that would love
to own this like it's a really high-end
very very good camera and it sits in our
cupboard with a really crappy lens on it
because it's just used for testing and
validation and like it's it's kind of
sad from that that point of too.
Occasionally I'll like take it out and
like, you know, let it see outside at
least, you know. But, uh, yeah. Um,
>> you just have a spot on your desk for,
you know, today's your day. Uh,
>> today's your day. Yeah. I think my my
funniest one is like that phase one
camera that they sent us, that medium
format camera. That thing is worth more
than my car. It's just a stupid bonkers
kind of system, this thing. And it's 150
megapixels. And I used it to take my
passport photo. So, in my passport is a
really really grainy de um you know step
down image that was originally from a
very very very high-end 150 megapixel
camera and that makes I don't know that
makes me smile. the person at
immigration, you know, at the border
doesn't care that like maybe they do
this. You never know, man. The warmth.
Uh
>> medium format would be that is like
I would love to play with that. I don't
have the, you know, uh budgetary means
to have one as a toy. Obviously,
>> I did say to the the folks at Phase One,
it's like, right, so we this camera
because they lent it. It's not mine.
It's not ours. So this is your camera
like you know we want to go out and
record some you know marketing shots for
our release with you. What's your
insure? Like do we insurance like what?
And they were like no no no no we don't
care. Take it out. If you smash it you
smash it. Like it's fine. Like we want
you to use the camera. So they're very
very like you know cool about it. Um so
maybe I should bring it to a conference
one day just so that people that are
interested can like could could try it.
>> That would be a fun uh almost marketing
kind of thing, right? like
>> you're shooting shots like medium format
shots. When I think of medium format, I
know there's Hasselblad and all these
like people use them for street
photography and stuff, but in my head,
>> my only real experience with people I
know is people who use them for
commercial photography where it's like
>> in a studio with and honestly like
shooting a passport is almost more what
I think of. Uh is it that kind where
it's like it's big, it's meant to be
mounted on something or is this a take
it out and shoot landscapes or something
with it? I believe the the three main
use cases for these things are um
landscape photography because you know
it stays still you can take very high
resolution very beautiful landscapes
studio photography like high-end fashion
magazines and things they tend to use
those big cameras and also uh a big
market for them is aerial photography so
you know like the satellite view on
Google maps or Apple Maps
>> again is mounted to something
>> isn't always satellite light is quite
often an array of these things or things
like it bolted to a plane and you know
they use it to you know very high
megapixels or that is good
>> but the studio version of this extremely
like they're not there's not a person
standing behind it hitting the shutter
right it's almost always probably
there's monitors set up and
>> there are multiple movies have parodyied
this but the one that comes to mind is
Austin Powers where there's like a
fashion shoot happening and there's a
very very sort of flamboyant character
with a camera like you know, saying all
sorts of stupid stuff and not, you know,
that isn't that far from the truth in
some situations. Like I've seen actual
photo shoots like that. They do tend to
be connected to a monitor as well, so
like clients and people can just see
what's being taken.
>> And is that where Casco comes in?
>> Yeah. Yeah. So like Cable can be that
for any camera if you wanted to like you
can connect it from your phone or iPad
or whatever to a screen. There's a
special like full screen external
display mode where it can be that as
well. So, actually that makes me think I
I had an episode, actually it just came
out a couple days ago as we record with
uh Joe from Teleprompter Pro, and he's
talked about how, you know, that's
similar where it's they're working a lot
with these sort of broadcast industry,
you know, type users. And he's talked
about like going into the field and like
shooting or at least watching people do
that and that kind of coming into
features and things that they add to the
app. Have you spent time in studios
seeing how people are using this and has
that informed stuff you've done in the
app?
>> A little bit. Yeah, I'd like to do it
more actually. Um I just need to figure
out a way to reach out to the right
people. But yeah, we've we've done it a
few times with especially like we've
worked with lighting manufacturers like
studio lighting and that has allowed us
to go into like you know actual studios
to see both the app and lighting being
used. Uh which is very interesting. Uh
does does the app do stuff with lighting
as well?
>> Not it doesn't. Um I'd like it to. is
the time thing again because I I need to
reverse engineer a bunch more things and
then figure out how it works. Yeah. Um
but yeah, I know I definitely think
there's a cool thing of being able to
script and automate lighting alongside
your camera in the same app. Like I
think that would be pretty cool. We've
been talking this whole time about we
call it Cascable, but the app at this
current time is called Cascable Studio.
And if you go to your website, you'll
see there's actually, you know, a number
of different apps. So yeah, what's the
story there? Why why have you sort of
split out into different apps versus
just shoving a bunch of different
features into the one mega app?
>> So, Cascal Studio is already too big.
Look, it's you know like it's got a
geotagging thing in it for instance for
you know applying location
to photos and like barely anybody uses
it.
>> They probably don't know it's there and
you can't market that as its own unique
feature.
>> I want to do a really good geotagging
app because there isn't one. That's not
fair. There are lots of geotagging. I
want to do my geotagging app. There we
go. That's a separate app. So, we I'm
kind of now in the position where I'm
like almost wanting to pull features
from the app and I'm kind of scared to
do so cuz it's going to like really
upset a very small number of people.
Um maybe we can give them a free copy of
like the new geotaging app once that
comes out, but I don't know. Um so,
it's kind of that like Caspal is a fully
fe Caspal studio. Casual Studio is a
fully featured app. Like it's a decade
old at this point. 11 Well, it's been
shipping 11 years actually. So, it's
more than well more well over a decade
old. Like the feature set it has is an
app like it's a full app and we you know
we add features you know more advanced
and we refine the features that are
there but like a whole new like category
almost
>> and it's still is it still onetime
purchase?
>> Yes, if you want it to be. So, we have
subscription and one time.
>> Ah, okay. Um, the non-subscription
purchase is now $100,
>> 99, which is expensive.
>> Well, but reflecting the fact that it's
a professional piece of software,
>> I don't think it's an unfair price at
all.
>> It's very rare we get complaints about
the price actually. So, maybe it's not
expensive enough. I don't know. But we
did add subscriptions a few years ago as
and we it was as a way to get in at a
lower cost or try the app out for a
month for a lower cost. And soon after
Adobe went subscription only for their
photography tools and that pissed off
basically the entire photography
industry like in one day. So I didn't
want to go subscription only
because our market is already very upset
about subscriptions basically. So it's a
you know the user confused right the
pedal comes up and there's the
non-subscription and the subscription
and I very specifically don't use the
word lifetime cuz we do charge have
started charging for updates like in the
traditional likeish traditionalish like
major updates
>> like new features.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Okay. you know, after a
certain amount of time, it's not like an
automated, you know, like if you have it
for X years, it doesn't get it. Like, we
make the decision, okay, well, this
feels like a big update and these
features are big new features. Is the
product that they're purchasing instead
of lifetime, do you call it like Cascal
Studio 3
or whatever? Like, how do you message
the fact that you're not buying
everything forever, but you're buying
this current set of features? So this is
interesting. So I never we never use the
word lifetime anywhere. We call it the
non-subscription option. And there's an
article on the website, a help article
that's like why is it not called
lifetime? And we explicitly say because
you're not it's not like it starts with
this question gets very difficult when
you ask who's lifetime like is it mine?
Is it yours? Is it all that makes sense
but most people on mobile aren't going
to probably open the website, right?
>> No, no, no. Exactly. So we we do um like
I need to put that in the app actually.
Um but we'll occasionally have somebody
email in saying hey I see there's a
subscription and a lifetime option and
ask a question and then I'll answer the
question also say you said lifetime it's
not lifetime look at this article. Um so
yeah um that's how we
>> but it hasn't been the source of a lot
of pain or strife or anything. No, I
I've
we occasionally get a question, hey,
it's not why why isn't it lifetime?
Like, I want it lifetime. And when I
send them out article, the answer is is
like, oh, okay.
>> Yeah, right. That makes sense.
>> Because we have we have enough history
of like not
screwing people over that we can look,
you can see people who bought the app
when it first came out in 2015 were
first asked for an upgrade in like 2022
or something.
>> Yeah. Like, you know, you get many
years. It's all we and we make the
promise that it's always the cheapest
So if you buy the non-subscription and
then you do the upgrades over time, that
will always be cheaper than subscribing
over the same kind of time period. And
that that that kind of like makes people
like, okay,
>> it is subscription and lifetime, but
there is a free mode as well, right?
>> So the the the free mode right now is
effectively equivalent to what you get
for free with your camera if you
download the manufacturer's own app.
>> Oh, interesting. Okay.
>> So you can use our app instead, but it
doesn't do anything more. to get more
you pay. Like our ratio of paid to
non-paid is about 25% paid which I think
is pretty high. Um in general we've
considered just getting rid of the free
tier entirely and just making it a
trial. I don't know if that would
actually convert anybody in the free
tier though. I mean my guess not knowing
literally anything about your market
really would be it would and you would
probably see higher conversions but
there is this sort of especially given
how you've described where you think
your growth is coming from. Um your free
tier is probably providing a significant
amount of the word of mouth.
>> Yeah, exactly. Um, that's all me
guessing. Like I every industry is a
little different, but especially since
you have essentially zero per user
costs, right? It's not like you're using
AI tokens for something or whatever.
Your free users aren't really a drag at
all. So like you would be trading
potentially word of mouth uh marketing,
which in a studio setting maybe is is
bigger than a lot of other apps um
non-social apps. I mean, you'd be
trading that for a higher conversion mo
most likely. I mean, we've seen we we
wrote about this in our like state of
subscriptions report thing this year,
but like a lot of people jumped on it
this year as a as a story of like I
should know the number off the top of my
head, but it switching to a hard payw
wall can make like your chart look silly
almost in terms of your conversions go
up, which makes sense, but like long
term, you know, a lot of people will
will subscribe for a week and instantly
cancel, so they use it or or whatever.
So, I don't know. It doesn't. It's a
trade-off, I guess.
>> Yeah. Like I I personally like I am an
indie developer and, you know, not one
that's had like an overnight success or
anything. Um, you know, I'm extremely
understanding and empathetic to the, you
know, the life of the indie developer.
And even then, if I open an app and it
forces me to do like a subscription with
a free trial, like I'm out. Like I I
won't complete the onboarding. Like it
just like nah. Well, it depends. I guess
if it's funny enough, you know,
>> if if there's a meme happening, I'll do
that, right? You know, I need to
generate the whatever. What do I look
like as an old man?
>> You know, I understand like weather apps
as an ongoing cost there, so sure. But
like, you know, in general, you know,
it's not I don't really like it. Um, so
yeah, I we've wondered about putting ads
in,
but then ads are often horrid.
>> Yeah. And and again because it's like uh
it's a professional app, right? It can
degrade that.
>> Yeah, exactly. One thing we've thought
um is were you aware of how Twitter did
apps? So the icon factory is Twitter
>> how they did like they did upgrades.
>> Oh. Uh yeah. Where they had
>> they had their own private ad network
basically and you could spend I think it
was $100 a week, month, oh no, something
>> to be in the app. And then they did it.
There was none of the horrid tracking
and stuff that the larger advertising
network had has.
>> There's actually a fellow again at Deep
Dish uh person.
>> Yes. Tyler, right?
>> Yes. He started is it guild ads.com? I
think that's the the website. It's
essentially taking Marco Arman's method
that he uses for Overcast, which is also
similar, and making it like
>> cross indie apps.
>> Yeah, exactly. So, um, for a little
while I've been idly thinking about
doing a similar thing to Twitter, but
like trying to sell spots to photography
like things, so you can advertise your
tripod in there or your camera or
whatever. And so that at least relevant
to the the people using the app. I I
don't really want to become an ad
network though. So, like when Tyler
started talking about this thing, I was
like, "Oh, so we I'm so I actually have
quite a uh I have a to-do this week to
contact him and actually try it." Um,
>> I just want to make sure I got that
right. Yeah, it's Guild Ads, which makes
me laugh because it looks like Guild
Dads. Um, which makes me laugh because
I'm in a group chat with him. That was
It started as like Missouri dads cuz
he's also from Missouri. Oh, really?
>> And so I can't not see that every time.
But yeah, Gildads.com is what it is.
>> Uh, yeah. I'm very curious to see how
that how that works out cuz Yeah, it's
basically try ads but not as gross.
>> Yeah. Yeah, exactly. So like I I'm I'm
we if we do ads it will be with that or
something like it very soon I think. So
just as an experiment to see if it cuz
you know he he himself said that one of
the reasons to have it is to push people
to get rid of them almost like you can
have like a
>> well Mueller who does carrot uh weather
>> he I don't know if you've seen his ads
that he has but he
>> I haven't it's amazing uh and selfishly
it's very beneficial to me. He basically
added them into his free tier as a way
to like basically as a perk for
upgrading, but they're all fake ads
>> uh that he made.
>> Oh, interesting.
>> And but most of them are random indie
apps. So like there is a dark noise ad
>> in there that he made that's it's I
forgot how it's phrased, but it's
something in his Carrot Weather voice.
So, it's like, you know, make all the
stupid sounds stop or it's funnier than
that cuz he's a lot funnier than me, but
it's like all these sort of goofy ads
that a lot of them are just made up or
they're random other indie apps. Um, and
he literally has it in there just as
another reason to kind of
>> uh upgrade is to just get rid of that
banner that takes up some space. Yeah, I
I do think we'll do that next because I
I don't think really getting rid of the
free tier is is going to be that
beneficial. Um like yeah I cuz like our
free we don't get a ton of support load
from free users like you know it's not
like like you say the app isn't costing
us any money to run
um other than fixedish costs for this
and that you know so it's not like you
know say hypothetically we just dump
that 75%.
So we only have paid the paid users we
have we wouldn't see any increased
revenue from that or reduced costs. So
yeah. Um yeah, I think we'll leave it
and just try other other ways to get
people to upgrade.
>> So we mentioned earlier like this, you
know, spinning off other apps. And you
mentioned an app that you're wanting to
build for GPS tagging, but you have a
number of other apps. There's like Photo
Scout, you have a webcam app.
>> We have Cascal Studio, which is the app
we've been talking about now. We have an
app called Cas Pro Webcam, which was our
COVID panic pivot that actually saved
the company. Um,
>> whoa. Well, we have to dive into that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, thankfully, as a an
accidental excellent business decision
many years ago, uh, I I pulled out the
camera connection logic and stuff into
its own framework. That is another
revenue stream for the company like we
licensed that out. So,
>> really? Yeah. So, we we have an SDK
product um that, you know, it's the same
API no matter the camera. So, you import
this thing and you can just connect to
every camera that Cascal Studio
supports. It's like 250.
>> Interesting. Okay.
>> And and then you can just build your app
and build the app and not have to care
that like, oh, Sony in this firmware
update changed this and blah blah blah
blah blah. Like, you know, we deal with
it. You have a very consistent API. Like
that's the sales pitch before it. So,
when Coronairus happened, people stopped
going outside, so all of the events got
cancelled. So, all of the event
photographers lost their jobs. So, all
of the event photographers stopped
buying photography apps. Basically, we
were kind of down the chain from that.
And we were like, h okay. So, and what
started happening was people were trying
to use their their real cameras that
they had as webcams because everybody
went remote work, right?
>> Well, and like reporters and all these
people Yeah. Everybody was trying to
figure it out
>> and there were, you know, there were
shortages of actual normal webcams. You
couldn't buy them. So, oh, well, we've
got this SDK. we saw ourselves just kind
of go. Um, so we went, "Oh, oh, we could
use the SDK to make a webcam, a virtual
webcam on the Mac, so you can connect
your camera and then it's a webcam." Um,
so from like idea to money was 3 weeks
and I'm very proud of that.
>> And and to money means a consumer app
that you built.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Selling copies to to
consumers. So had the SDK. It's a very
simple Mac app. The main complexity was
working out like the virtual webcam kind
of architecture of Mac OS, but we could
just like ship that real quick and then
that saved the day basically that filled
in the revenue and so yeah it really did
like it leveled off your you know
aggregate revenue. Did has that
continued to be kind of an important
piece or when the world kind of went
back to more normal did that slowly
level off to a smaller amount and cas
died off fairly significantly. the
camera manufacturer's also kind of
eventually cotton on and now often if
you buy a new camera it has a webcam
mode in it. So what um we need to do now
I think the future for that app is
actually making it pro so like you can
support multiple cameras connected and
like you know other features like that
so you
>> learn what the more advanced users are
trying to
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. And make it an
advanced product. Yeah. It still sells
okay but it's it's you know it's it's on
the maintenance schedule right now. Um
and yeah, so like I do believe in having
multiple revenue streams like you know.
>> Yeah. And in those cases too like those
are while they feel similar, it's
actually like you just said it's very
different audiences actually.
>> Um it uses a camera
market changes or whatever.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and then your other app is or the
other big one that I know about is photo
scout. Uh what's the story there? It was
an idea for a feature for Cascal Studio
from years ago. Years and years and
years ago. Thankfully, I didn't try to
put in the app because it it was it was
already full. And
the tagline for it is you say where we
say when. So the idea is like I need to
work on the elevator pitch for that. But
you want to take a cool photo. You're at
the beach. You want a really beautiful
sunset. Say you can say okay well I want
to be here. I want the sunset to be like
particularly vibrant. I want there to be
not a lot of cloud cover so you can
actually see it. I don't want it to be
too windy cuz I want my hair to look
good. Add it in. You put the app away
and you'll get a push notification that
says, "Okay, if you go back there at
this time, yeah, you'll get the photo
you want." Um, and we we have like, you
know, modules for the northern lights
and we have uh like so, you know, if the
northern lights are happening and the cl
the sky is clear so you can actually see
it, you know, you you'll get notified.
So, it's looking at what is that KPI? Is
that what that's called? For the
Northern Lights.
>> Yes. Yeah. Yeah. So, so we're kind of
hooked into the um Nora, is it? The
American Weather Association like thing
forecast for that. Um we do position of
the sun and the moon and things in the
sky. So, if you want a comedy photo of a
statue pointing at the sun or whatever,
you can do that. Like, you know, so it
has
>> I imagine is this one that you also see
spikes uh during like solar events.
>> Exactly.
>> Yeah. funny about the statue thing. Um
cuz we were trying to like pitch it to,
you know, for marketing and to like
Apple folks to get, you know, featured
and all that kind of stuff. So I went
around Stockholm and
like took, you know, did the example of
like having a statue pointing at the
sun, right? So you the screenshot would
be, you know, the statue with the box in
the sky saying, "All right, I want the
sun to be here, please." So, I did all
that and I got back and I was looking
through the photos. I said, and I
realized thankfully in time that most of
the stat a lot of the statues in
Stockholm
are of guys with no clothing.
>> Uh, and I couldn't really send them to
to Apple. Um, yeah, it is kind of in
that weird uh, you know, it's art
generally speaking. Obviously, it's in a
public setting, but it that with Apple,
you feel like you want to be extra extra
extra careful with everything. Yeah,
>> exactly. So, then we went on vacation.
We connected through Paris and we had a
day in Paris. Um, oh, the Eiffel Tower.
So, our examples are now like, you know,
the sun sitting on top of the Eiffel
Tower or
>> which is probably a more common, you
know,
>> or the sun setting through the arctic
triumph. So, the sun is in the arch, the
king. Oh, that's actually and we got
those photos as well. So, we've actually
got real examples of the app in use. Um,
yeah. So, so that that's the other app
and that's um yeah, that that's not
Cascal Studio is our bread winner and I
think
our main problem with photo scout is
that it's very easy to show. Like if you
show it to someone, oh, that's really
cool. I get it. But like describing it
in a in an advert is really difficult.
And I and we haven't cracked that yet.
So, one of our tasks this year Yeah.
um is to to figure that out and get it
get it marketed properly because I think
it's a great app. I love it. Like it's
really cool.
>> Yeah. Well, and I mean that's a it's a
thing I do frequently. Uh I've used some
different like ones that are just
focused on sun before. Um but I knew the
name of it and I had never tried it
until you know we started talking or
maybe you mentioned it during the the
podcast you did before. Um, but it is
now on my phone as a like because I I do
all these weird little videos all the
time and like do I want this during
golden hour or do I sometimes I want it
to be raining because it's funnier or
whatever. And so understanding those
weird combinations of things is is
actually a kind of somewhat frequent
thing.
>> Yeah. One thing I wanted to add, it's on
our list is to do it has been raining
but it is no longer raining.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So like a city is beautiful
in that if it's dark and it's wet but it
isn't raining you know the reflections
everywhere like you can get some really
cool shots there. So like that's
something to add in you know stuff like
that. Um yeah it's just figuring out how
to market it because it's it's tricky.
Awesome. Well we are uh we are we are at
the end here but uh you know I can't let
you go without asking the question I ask
everyone to end the show which is uh
what's a person or people out there that
inspire you and your work that you'd
recommend uh others check out? I'm
actually going to give two then if one
one's developing related and one isn't
if that's okay. I
>> fine I guess.
>> Fine. Okay. Really tight shift here
normally.
>> Yeah. Yeah. First one is my father. He's
passed away. He's also not a developer
but he did as I said earlier run a his
own business doing uh journalism.
Growing up with that kind of just put
into me that well that's just a
perfectly normal thing to do is to have
your own business. And that is why it's
not why I'm an indie developer, but it's
why I considered that I could be cuz
it's like completely normal. It's like,
well, yeah, I'll just do my own business
like dad did, you know, whatever. So
that that's just kind of ingrained into
me that it's it's completely possible
for, you know, anybody to do with so
much less scary thing. And it is hard
work.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Because it's it's not
it's just it's just what dad did, right?
So So that that's one. Uh and the other
one developer wise is Will Shipley.
>> Okay.
>> So he now he now works for Apple. The
big thing he was famous for is an app
called Delicious Library. That was a Mac
app that came out in
mid200s, I want to say. Um, it's fairly
it was a Mac OS 10 app, but it was
fairly early in Mac OS 10. And
it was basically a library for
managing well, it was an app for
managing your media library, like your
DVDs and your Blu-rays and your books
and stuff. So you know it had like a
barcode scanner so you could scan your
thing and it would look look up all the
metadata for the thing you scanned and
it' put it on the shelf and you could
you know it was very beautiful. It's
very very very skeworphic like it was
that era of apps.
>> The delicious era.
>> The delicious era. It started the
delicious era like of apps that were
like that like very very beautiful very
very very polished. Ton of work going
into that. So that that always inspired
me a lot just just the the what he was
putting out was like you know what you
could do on the Mac. Um but also like
I'd never saw him in I don't think I've
ever met him but I've never seen him
speak in person but I've seen him you
know like recordings of talks he's given
here and there and it's clear he's a
very smart developer and also a very
smart business person and that that you
know inspired me and there there was one
talk I heard I think it's just an audio
recording of him give he was talking
about how he did coupon codes for for
something I can't remember the context
of he had a coupon code that gave
somebody a discount and somebody put
their hand up and asked like yeah but
your app is $50 What happens if somebody
shares the code and then they get your
app for $20? And his answer is like,
well, I take that $20.
>> Yes. Yes. Oh, man. I think
>> I love that answer. And I think about it
like still when I'm thinking about stuff
like that, it's like, well, if we're
doing a promo and somebody gets it that
they shouldn't, so we'll just take their
money. It's fine. like you know and and
that just kind of that his whole
attitude in in running the business and
he was uh somebody I kind of aspired to
be if you like the products he put out
and just the kind of the way he run the
business as well panic cable sassa and
that lot of panic is also kind of in
that thing you know like independent Mac
shop that you know they're a lot bigger
than I think I aspire to be now but
still like you know I used their apps
back in Mac OS 8 and 9 like their MP3
player and their file transfer thing and
yeah I don't know they've always been
another sort of indie company that I've
kind of aspired to to So yeah, try and
get the panic folks on.
>> You know, they're in that category that
from day one they have been on my list
and uh I've had some heroes, many heroes
of mine on the show, but I still have
never been brave enough to uh to, you
know, reach out. Uh
>> yeah,
>> I've I've met Cable like once or twice
at an event, but you know, in one of
those like I love your work, you know,
and then he moves on to the next
handshake kind of thing. So like
>> uh but yes I I I I should one definitely
should one of these days.
>> Photo Scout has a theme song because of
panic like it has music in the on
boarding. If you open photo scout and
you unmute your phone and you sit on the
on boarding so nobody will see it hear
it. There's a song that plays and if you
stay on the on boarding the song has
like weather elements in the sound and
the weather on the on boarding in the
graphics will change based on the music.
>> That's fantastic. So like storm comes in
and it
>> breaking. Yeah. Everybody go download it
and find it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I loved it. And I did that
because Panic had an app on the iPad. I
think it's called Status Board.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> And their on boarding had like some
elevator music like playing in the
background when you went through the on
boarding and I really like that. So I
kind of copied that. Um yeah.
>> Ah fantastic. Those are very very good.
Uh all right. So where uh can people
find you on the internet uh if they can?
and uh and Cascal.
>> Yeah. So, Cascal is at cascal.se.
So, casc.
That's where all my apps are. I'm Iendac
on everywhere. So, I keen DAC. So, I'm
on Master Dawn. I'm on Blue Sky.
Sometimes my website is Iend.ac.
Again, in the history of having names
and things that people can't pronounce
or remember, you know, I make it really
hard to find it. Honestly, if you search
my name on Google and stuff, it'll come
up. Uh, so I have a blog there where I
write very long blog posts very
occasionally. I can deck everywhere
basically.
>> Perfect. And of course, we'll have uh
we'll have links in the show notes for
that for that. All right. Well, thank
you again for coming and thank you all
for uh listening this far. Uh, Launched
is a part of the Revenue Cat podcast
family. Uh if you're interested in
learning more about the growth side of
the mobile app business, you should
check out Subub uh which is run by my,
you know, much more uh professional and
adult colleague, uh David Barnard. Uh
and then of course you can check out
ravonycat.com to learn about the easiest
way to grow and monetize your mobile app
business. And uh for everything
launched, go to launchedfm.com,
which is also pretty much our handle uh
everywhere on the internet. And if you
don't already, you should uh check out
our YouTube channel because this is a
video podcast now. Uh and we put a lot
of work into, you know, our faces uh for
for this. So yeah, you should check that
out. It's a it's a lot of fun. And uh
I'll see you all in two weeks. Bye.